[
{
    "question": "Ne far ðu <strong>æfter</strong> fremdum godum - Do not go #### strange gods",
    "correctAnswer": "after",
    "explanation": "Here 'æfter' translates to 'after'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Ær sunnan his nama soþfæst standeþ, biþ his setl <strong>ær</strong> swylce ðonne mona - His name is present before the sun; his seat likewise exists at a time #### the moon did",
    "correctAnswer": "before",
    "explanation": "Here 'ær' translates to 'before'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Ðonne wile Dryhten sylf dæda gehyran <strong>æt</strong> ealra monna gehwam - Then will the Lord himself hear of the deeds #### all sorts of men",
    "correctAnswer": "from",
    "explanation": "Here 'æt' translates to 'from'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Eac he witgode <strong>be</strong> þære wræce þe æfter him wurþan sceolde þam folce - Also he prophecised #### the exile which would befall the Jewish people",
    "correctAnswer": "about",
    "explanation": "Here 'be' translates to 'about'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Læg se fula leap gesne <strong>beæftan</strong> him - The foul body lay #### them",
    "correctAnswer": "behind",
    "explanation": "Here 'beæftan' translates to 'behind'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Hwa ne wafaþ ðæs, ðæt ða steorran scinaþ <strong>beforan</strong> ðam monan, and ne beforan ðære sunnan - Who wonders not at this, that the stars shine #### the moon, and not before the sun?",
    "correctAnswer": "before",
    "explanation": "Here 'beforan' translates to 'before'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Nu ic eow sende swa swa lamb <strong>betweox</strong> wulfas - Now I send you just like a lamb #### wolves",
    "correctAnswer": "between",
    "explanation": "Here 'betweox' translates to 'between'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "He cydde fela be Cristes godcundnysse, hu he ecelice <strong>butan</strong> angynne of his Fæder acenned is - He made known many things concerning Christ's divinity, how he eternally #### beginning was begotten of his Father",
    "correctAnswer": "without",
    "explanation": "Here 'butan' translates to 'without'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Gif ðu sunu age, oððe swæsne mæg, oððe freond ænigne <strong>eac</strong> ðissum idesum, alaide of ðysse leod-byrig - If you have a son, or beloved kinsman, or any friend #### these ladies, lead them from this city",
    "correctAnswer": "including",
    "explanation": "Here 'eac' translates to 'including'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Eardas rume Meotud arærde <strong>for</strong> moncynne - The Creator established spacious lands #### mankind",
    "correctAnswer": "for",
    "explanation": "Here 'for' translates to 'for'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Hie eodon <strong>fram</strong> Norwege mid miclum scipfierde ⁠— They came #### Norway with a large navy",
    "correctAnswer": "from",
    "explanation": "Here 'fram' translates to 'from'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Þa Deniscan leode ferdon <strong>mid</strong> sciphere hergiende ond sleande wide geond land — The Danish people travelled #### a navy plundering and killing widely around the land",
    "correctAnswer": "with",
    "explanation": "Here 'mid' translates to 'with'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Se sweta mete ðe hie heton monna se him cuom <strong>of</strong> hefonum⁠ — The sweet meats that they call mana which comes #### heaven",
    "correctAnswer": "from",
    "explanation": "Here 'of' translates to 'from'",
    "commonMistakes": [
        {
            "incorrectAnswer": "of",
            "explanation": ""
        }
    ]
},
{
    "question": "He eode eft <strong>ongean</strong> to þæm bearnum - He went back #### the children",
    "correctAnswer": "towards",
    "explanation": "Here 'ongean' translates to 'towards'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Þa metton hie .xvi. scipu wicenga, and <strong>wiþ</strong> ða gefuhton - Then they met 16 viking ships and fought #### them",
    "correctAnswer": "against",
    "explanation": "Here 'wiþ' translates to 'against'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Ða wæs þær, <strong>binnan</strong> þære byrig Hierusalem, sum Godes mann, and his nama wæs Symeon - There was there, #### the city of Jerusalem, a man of God, and his name was Simeon",
    "correctAnswer": "in|within",
    "explanation": "Here 'binnan' translates to 'in'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Se steorra <strong>bufan</strong> Cristes gesthuse ætstod - The star stopped #### Christ's inn",
    "correctAnswer": "above",
    "explanation": "Here 'bufan' translates to 'above'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "He wæs bebyrged <strong>innan</strong> ðære cyrican - He was buried #### the church",
    "correctAnswer": "in",
    "explanation": "Here 'innan' translates to 'in'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Þa wicingas woldon þæt þa Deniscan þegnas ricsoden <strong>ofer</strong> Englalande - The Vikings wished that the Danish thanes ruled #### England",
    "correctAnswer": "over",
    "explanation": "Here 'ofer' translates to 'over'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "His heafod hie drogon <strong>geond</strong> þa burh — They dragged his head #### the town",
    "correctAnswer": "through",
    "explanation": "Here 'geond' translates to 'through'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Ic geanbidode swiðe wel <strong>oð</strong> ic wisse hwæt ðu woldest — I waited very willingly #### I knew what you wanted",
    "correctAnswer": "until",
    "explanation": "Here 'oð' translates to 'until'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Ða wæron wit twegen on anum olfende <strong>þurh</strong> þæt rume westen⁠ — Then we two were on a camel travelling #### that enormous desert",
    "correctAnswer": "through",
    "explanation": "Here 'þurh' translates to 'through'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "He wearp hine on þæt morðer <strong>innan</strong> - He threw him #### the torment within,",
    "correctAnswer": "into",
    "explanation": "Here 'innan' translates to 'into'",
    "commonMistakes": []
},
{
    "question": "Ac licgað me <strong>ymb</strong> irenbenda, rideð racentan sal - But #### me there lies iron bonds, a cable of chain rides over me",
    "correctAnswer": "around",
    "explanation": "Here 'ymb' translates to 'around'",
    "commonMistakes": []
}
]